Digitalize a piece of real fabric.
Need to carry out
Physical attribute testing
And text scanning and processing.
Then merge them into a complete digital fabric.
Specific operation process
We will explain in the next chapter.
Here we first understand the basic application of Clover fabric.
Next, open the core tool to learn Clover fabric.
That is, in the library.
Select the Clover training in Connect.
Core tool to learn Clover fabric.
Then press the Y on the keyboard to close the library.
First, at the right side of the object window, click on the fabric.
See the attribute editor below.
A fabric contains information attributes,
material attributes and physical attributes.
See the information attribute.
The information contains the name of the fabric.
Product code, structure, supplier, all information.
Open the triangle on the right side of the structure, you can see its ingredients.
You can also use the information you need to fill in.
Edit it.
For example, the name of the fabric is changed.
And the structure can be filled in according to the type of the fabric.
For example, fill in as shrinkage.
Supplier below.
All information such as users can be filled in.
Look down.
It is the material information of the fabric.
It contains all the information of the material effect of the current expression of the fabric.
The current fabric already has the texture and the hair line.
These are the two stickers that the fabric must have.
We can see the
color.
Open the color tool.
The left side is the user's custom color.
You can customize the color according to its RGB value or CMYK value.
You can also use the color meter to absorb the color on the current screen.
Press ESC to exit the suction function.
The right side is the color library.
It includes the Pantone color library, YKK color library and ColorRow color library.
You can search for colors by entering the color number.
It is necessary to note that the color currently selected will be directly stacked on the texture.
So we need to use the buffer or replacement below.
To check the correct color.
The buffer will reduce the saturation of the entire base color.
And remove the color.
Transform it into a gray or black and white picture.
After choosing the buffer.
You can see that the color of the current clothing has turned white.
And there are two options below the buffer.
Shadow intensity and shadow brightness.
By adjusting the shadow intensity.
You can adjust the shadow effect of the texture.
And the shadow brightness.
You can adjust the texture brightness.
Replace is to quickly change the color of the pure color plant.
Switch to a new color.
It will not lose the delicacy and accuracy of the selected texture.
After charging or replacing the color.
Open the color tool again.
Choose color block.
You can see that when applying different color blocks.
The color of the background is the same as the color block.
Here we do not apply color.
Select cancel to close the color tool.
The filter image is a texture image.
Numeric image with texture and color information.
Click the right button to find it.
confirm to select them.
Let's open the detail over here.
Fresh as the unwillingness.
Let's change it.
You can choose to create a new library in the library window.
Then add a folder.
Add the material we have downloaded to the library window.
Select the folder.
Then double-click to open the next layer of the file.
Drag this dot pattern to the texture here.
Loosen the left mouse button to apply the texture.
Close the library.
At this time, the clothing fabric is applied to the dot pattern.
Then use the editor texture tool.
Enlarge and shrink in the 2D or 3D window.
And rotate this texture.
You can also move the position of the texture.
Adjust the effect of the texture on the clothing.
Accurate adjustment of the size of the texture.
You can click the right button when you shrink the texture.
A pop-up window appears.
Enter data to adjust the size of the texture.
You can also enter data in the right mouse button.
Adjust the size of the texture.
Then add the line art.
The line art can show theGirling effect more realistically.
Click the trash can on the right.
You can delete the current line art.
Open the art drawer.
Open the drawing library, select the color of the cloud drawing library, and the color of the line drawing.
You can choose a line drawing, drag it to the position of the line drawing,
release the left mouse button, and then adjust the strength of the line drawing.
By adjusting the auto-tune of the fabric, you can see the changes in the 3D window.
Close the drawing library.
The fabric can also be set.
Front, back, side materials.
If you encounter fabrics with different materials on the front and back,
you can choose the back, and cancel the use of the same material on the front.
Then adjust the material effect of the back material according to your needs.
Next, you can see the fabric preset.
Open the triangle next to the type.
There are many material options here.
Some of them need to be checked in the rendering window for material effects.
Next, we use two pictures to understand the effect of the preset of different materials on the fabric.
You can see the first picture.
Here, there are fabrics with gloss, fabric silk color nails, leather, tanning cloth, fur, wool, etc.
These material types are often used on the fabric.
The second picture includes glass, necklaces, lights, gems, metals, etc.
These material types often appear in
materials, accessories, and props.
Finally, come to the bottom.
Physical properties.
Here are some previews of fabric physical properties.
Switch previews.
Open the simulation.
Check the hammering effect of the fabric under different physical properties.
Then add some fabric.
In the material window, select the plus sign.
You can add a default fabric.
Open the sketchbook.
There are many common fabrics included in the sketchbook.
For your use, you can drag the fabric to the material window from the sketchbook window.
Select V2, shrink, fold, 1.
Drag it to the material window.
Then you can double-click the fabric.
Drag V2, shrink, fold, 2 to the material window.
Close the sketchbook.
Here I will operate the demonstration.
The fabric in the local file folder can also be added to the material window by dragging.
The fabric in the local file folder can also be added to the material window.
We can also copy a fabric in the material window.
Select it, select copy, and adjust its parameters.
For example, add a color.
Select the application and close it.
You will get a different color of the fabric.
Next, apply the fabric to the clothing.
Use the adjustment panel tool.
Select the belt panel.
On the right side of the material window, V2, shrink, fold, 2, there is a small arrow, single click.
You can see that the fabric has been applied to the plate.
We can also select the front and back of the clothing.
Drag V2, shrink, fold, 1 directly from the material window.
Loosen the left mouse button.
Apply the fabric to the plate.
In the material window, we can also adjust the order of the fabric by dragging.
And we can double-click to rename the fabric.
For example, we can rename the fabric we copied to the name of the fabric.
Next, we can add a new fabric group to the material window.
If the clothing has multiple layers or multiple pieces,
it can be easily managed by dividing the group.
We can also drag the upper fabric to the other group for management.
Then, if there is no fabric applied to the clothing,
you can click on the small trash can on the right side of the fabric.
Delete the fabric.
You can also click on the right button.
Select to delete all unused fabrics or only delete the current fabric.
You can see that there is still a reset.
Reset refers to restoring the fabric to the default fabric.
Next, we can delete the group.
Click on the small trash can next to the group to delete it.
You can see that the new fabric is added to the fabric.
Then, we can see the corresponding relationship between the fabric and the fabric.
Click on the fabric of the material window.
You can see that the fabric of the fabric applied is yellow.
And click on the next fabric.
You can see that the fabric applied to the belt fabric at this time.
Click on the fabric at the top.
You can see the fabric applied to the fabric.
When you click on the sheet, the corresponding fabric applied to it will turn blue in the object window.
The fabric can also be stored and opened.
We can choose this wave fabric, and then choose Save here.
Click Confirm.
We can see that it can be renamed to the current fabric, and the current fabric storage type is ZFAB format.
Select Save.
The fabric can also be opened.
For example, open this pattern fabric for the wave fabric we just saved.
Click Open.
Find this wave fabric.
You can see that
this wave fabric has also been opened.
Thanks for watching today's video.
We'll be building theال duck dive surface to theしか
We'll be building the look in the future.
Have a nice day.
Be brave
Don't forget to like and subscribe
We will see you soon
See you next time